A Guide to the L.F. Payne, Jr. Papers, 1988-1997
Library of Virginia
- Series IV. Press Files, 1994-1997., Extent: 10 boxes. (Box 39-48)
  - Clippings, 1996 (July). (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1996 (August). (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1996 (September). (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Photographs. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Payne Leads Fight for Balanced Budget, 4 January 1995. (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Lacy Ward Joins Payne Staff, 9 January 1995. (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Payne Co-Sponsors Bill on Unfunded Mandates, 10 January 1995. (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Payne Announces White House Conference on Aging, 19 January 1995. (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Balanced Budget Amendment, 20 January 1995. (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - "Pass the Balanced Budget Amendment," Op-ed, Danville Register, 22 January 1995. (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Tobacco Growers Appreciation Award, 23 January 1995. (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Balanced Budget Amendment, 23 January 1995. (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Payne Urges Clinton Not to Sell SEPA, 24 January 1995. (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - State of the Union Reaction, 25 January 1995. (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Payne Hails Passage of Balanced Budget Amendment, 26 January 1995. (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - Floor Speech - General Debate on the Balanced Budget Amendment, 26 January 1995. (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Civil Engineers in Charlottesville Address (Cancelled), 28 January 1995. (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - Article - Welfare Reform (Virginia Municipal League), 2 February 1995. (Box 42, Folder 22)
  - Students from Presidential Classroom, 3 February 1995. (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - Federal Grant Award to Waid Recreation Area, 8 February 1995. (Box 42, Folder 24)
  - Self-Employed to Receive Tax Help Under House Bill, 9 February 1995. (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - Brownsville Students Visit, 10 February 1995. (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - Payne Warns of Job Losses Under CBI Parity, 10 February 1995. (Box 42, Folder 27)
  - Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner, 11 February 1995. (Box 42, Folder 28)
  - Opinion Survey, February 1995. (Box 42, Folder 29)
  - Coalition for America, 14 February 1995. (Box 42, Folder 30)
  - Gtants for Regional Airports, 17 February 1995. (Box 42, Folder 31)
  - Academy Day Set for March 18th in Charlottesville, 21 February 1995. (Box 42, Folder 32)
  - Buckingham Clinic Gets Federal Grant, 23 February 1995. (Box 42, Folder 33)
  - House Approves Payne Amendment on Textile Import Rules, 23 February 1995. (Box 42, Folder 34)
  - Talking Points, Charlottesville Dinner, 3 March 1995. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Payne Renews Call for I-73 Through Franklin and Henry Counties, 8 March 1995. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Payne Criticizes Archer Proposal, 9 March 1995. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Lake Gaston Pipeline, 9 March 1995. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - G.O.P. Tax Cut Proposal, 14 March 1995. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Payne Votes to Cut Committee Budgets, 15 March 1995. (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Congressional Arts Competition, 7 March 1995. (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - School Lunch Program, 20 March 1995. (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - "The Wrong Tax Cut at the Wrong Time," Op-ed, Charlottesville Daily Progress, 22 March 1995. (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Continuation of Danville's Essential Air Service, 23 March 1995. (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Student Leadership Conference, 24 March 1995. (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Coalition Press Conference on Welfare Reform, 24 March 1995. (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Payne Opposes CBI Parity Bill, 29 March 1995. (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Payne Urges Funding for Danville Armory, 30 March 1995. (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - House Approves Tax Deduction for Self-Employed, 30 March 1995. (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Young Democrats of Virginia, 1 April 1995. (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Federal Aid Approved for Former Sara Lee Workers, 3 April 1995. (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Payne Calls Tax Cut Irresponsible, 4 April 1995. (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Payne Speaks Out Against Tax Cuts, 5 April 1995. (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Lake Gaston Settlement, 7 April 1995. (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Fifth District Art Competition, 13 April 1995. (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Power Marketing Administrations, 14 April 1995. (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Payne Tours Senior Citizens Centers, 17 April 1995. (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - BGF Industries, South Hill, 23 April 1995. (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Rocky Mount Wastewater Treatment Plant Dedication, 26 April 1995. (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - "Pittsylvania 2000," 26 April 1995. (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Virginia Society of Internal Medicine, 29 April 1995. (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - South Hill VFW Loyalty Day Parade, 29 April 1995. (Box 43, Folder 28)
  - Forest Middle School Dedication, 30 April 1995. (Box 43, Folder 29)
  - Payne Holds Post Office Hours, May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Payne Renews Call for FERC to Scrap Gaston Study, 3 May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Chamber of Commerce, 9 May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Payne and Southside Legislators on Lake Gaston, 10 May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Payne Hails Decision on Textile and Apparel Imports, 11 May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Floor Statement on Budget Resolution, 17 May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Payne Urges No Sale on Power Marketing Administrations, 18 May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Payne Defends Power Marketing Administrations, 18 May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Payne Names Elam to White House Tourism Conference, 18 May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Payne Announces One-on-One Meetings, 18 May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Clarksville Airport Improvements, 19 May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Payne to Hold Community One-on-Ones, 25 May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Bedford Girl Scout Flap, 25 May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Bedford Memorial Day Celebration, 29 May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Leaf Tobacco Exporters Association, 30 May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Society of Certified Public Accountants, 30 May 1995. (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Town Meetings, 31 May and 1 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Payne and Business Leaders on Lake Gaston, 1 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Fifth District Housing Conference, 1 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - "Lake Gaston Pipeline Dispute Affects Entire Commonwealth," Op-ed, Danville Register and Bee, 3 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - "All Virginians Have a Stake in Pipeline Dispute," Op-ed, Richmond Times-Dispatch, 5 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - "Spirit of Enterprise" Award, 7 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Nomination of Virginia Museum of Natural History Award, 8 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Payne Issues Final FERC Comments, 9 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - "Tobacco and the 104th Congress," Philip Morris Conference, Charlotte, North Carolina, 12 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - Payne Addresses BRAC Commission, 13 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 26)
  - Payne Urges Governors to Delay Action on Pipeline Compact, 15 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 27)
  - Senator Houck Fundraiser, 17 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 28)
  - Piney River Project Grant Award, 21 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 29)
  - Campbell County RSVP Program Grant Award, 22 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 30)
  - Payne Votes to Reduce Congressional Budgets, 22 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 31)
  - Closure of Fort Pickett, 23 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 32)
  - Federal Aid for Martinsville Fire Victims, 28 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 33)
  - Decision Not to Hold Lake Gaston Special Session, 28 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 34)
  - Payne Urges FERC to Suspend Action on Lake Gaston, 29 June 1995. (Box 44, Folder 35)
  - Campbell County Disaster Declaration, 3 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Letter to Governor Regarding Lake Gaston Negotiations, 3 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Breakdown of Lake Gaston Negotiations, 6 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - FERC Final Environmental Impact Statement on Lake Gaston, 7 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Association of American Railroads' Legislative Conference, Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 7-9 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Associated Builders and Contractors Award, 11 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Lake Country RSVP Program Gets Award, 11 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Danville Wins Grant to Combat Drug Use, 12 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Payne Urges Rejection of Anti-Tobacco Regulations, 13 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Payne, Colleagues Attack Proposal Tobacco Regulations, 14 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Southside Virginia Community College Telecommunications Grant, 19 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Danville Tobacco Market Opening, 19 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Payne Hails House Vote on Tobacco, 20 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Chatham Approved for USDA Loan to Upgrade Water Lines, 27 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Legislators Agree on I-73, 27 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Payne Defends Economic Development Administration, 27 July 1995. (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Meeting Cards for August One-on-One Visits, 1 August 1995. (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Ways and Means Trip to Chile, 4-12 August 1995. (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Payne Reacts to Clinton Announcement on FDA, 10 August 1995. (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - August Town Meetings, 15-17 August 1995. (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Payne Tours Local Hospitals, 22 August 1995. (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Virginia Bankers Association, Lynchburg, 22 August 1995. (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Barbara Coleman Fundraiser, 22 August 1995. (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Medicare Forum, 24 August 1995. (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - "Proposals Threaten Domestic Tobacco Industry," Virginia Farmer, 1 September 1995. (Box 45, Folder 25)
  - Chase City Industrial Site Wins EDA Grant, 5 September 1995. (Box 45, Folder 26)
  - Payne Introduces Bill to Bar New Tobacco Regulations, 7 September 1995. (Box 45, Folder 27)
  - Key House Panel Approves Local Route for I-73, 8 September 1995. (Box 45, Folder 28)
  - News Conference: Payne on CBI Parity, 12 September 1995. (Box 45, Folder 29)
  - Campbell County School System Wins Technology Grant, 13 September 1995. (Box 45, Folder 30)
  - Patrick Henry Community College Wins $1.6 Million Grant, 13 September 1995. (Box 45, Folder 31)
  - Rules of Origin Preserved by House Committee, 14 September 1995. (Box 45, Folder 32)
  - Joyce Glaise Fundraiser, 16 September 1995. (Box 45, Folder 33)
  - "Bypassing Congress to Regulate Tobacco is a Dangerous Precedent," Op-ed, Richmond Times-Dispatch, 19 September 1995. (Box 45, Folder 34)
  - Payne Supports PMA's (Hold), 19 September 1995. (Box 45, Folder 35)
  - House Approves National Highway System, 20 September 1995. (Box 45, Folder 36)
  - Payne Calls Medicare Proposal "Extreme," 20 September 1995. (Box 45, Folder 37)
  - HUD to Finance Danville Housing Project for Elderly, 3 October 1995. (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Delegation Luncheon, 11 October 1995. (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Coalition Unveils Its Budget Reconciliation Alternative, 13 October 1995. (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Payne Urges Delay of Tobacco Comment Period, 15 October 1995. (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Appomattox Railroad Parade, 14 October 1995. (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - DCCC Wintergreen Golf Tournament, 15 October 1995. (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Payne Hails Decision to Drop PMA Sale, 16 October 1995. (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Floor Speech - Support the Coalition Budget, 25 October 1995. (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Floor Speech - Payne on Medicare Parts of Coalition Budget, 25 October 1995. (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - "Coalition Offers Better Plan to Balance Budget," Op-ed, Lynchburg News and Advance, 26 October 1995. (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Lew Parker Fundraiser, 29 October 1995. (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Payne Says Study Needed of Gambling in U.S., 31 October 1995. (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - "The Right Road to a Balanced Budget," Op-ed, 3 November 1995. (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Democrats Win Big, 8 November 1995. (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - American Legion Post 104, Appomattox, Veterans Day Service, 11 November 1995. (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Nelson Community Care Network Grant Announcement, 13 November 1995. (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Coalition Budget Press Conference, 14 November 1995. (Box 46, Folder 17-18)
  - Payne Introduces Bill to Block Lake Gaston Pipeline, 16 November 1995. (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Payne, Colleagues Urge Clinton to Agree to Budget, 17 November 1995. (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Floor Speech - Payne on Budget Reconciliation Conference Report, 17 November 1995. (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Fifth District Economic Development Conference, 17 November 1995. (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - Congress Clears I-73 Bill for President, 20 November 1995. (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - Lake Gaston Lawsuit, 22 November 1995. (Box 46, Folder 24)
  - Payne Warns That Budget Could Hurt Farm Economy, 27 November 1995. (Box 46, Folder 25)
  - President's Policy on Bosnia, 28 November 1995. (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - Fifth District Economic Development Conference, 4 December 1995. (Box 46, Folder 27)
  - Rural Areas Are Big Winners on Information Superhighway, 5 December 1995. (Box 46, Folder 28)
  - Coalition Members React to Budget Veto, 7 December 1995. (Box 46, Folder 29)
  - Coalition Press Conference with American Hospital Association, 14 December 1995. (Box 46, Folder 30)
  - Newsletter, December 1995. (Box 46, Folder 31)
  - Payne Calls for End to Budget Stalemate, 20 December 1995. (Box 46, Folder 32)
  - Payne, Colleagues Place Coalition Budget on Negotiating Table, 21 December 1995. (Box 46, Folder 33)
  - Payne Renews Call to Keep CBI Parity Out of Budget Plan, 21 December 1995. (Box 46, Folder 34)
  - Floor Speech - Support the Coalition Budget, 21 December 1995. (Box 46, Folder 35)
  - Coalition Pursues New Course to End Impasse, 4 January 1996. (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Floor Speech - Partial Re-Opening of Federal Government, 5 January 1996. (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Cumberland County Wins Grant for Sewer Improvements, 10 January 1996. (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - "Don't Wait for Election to Balance the Budget," Op-ed, 17 January 1996. (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Payne Renews Call for Withdrawal of Proposed FDA Tobacco Regulations, 19 January 1996. (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Special Mailing - Payne Provides Year End Report, 22 January 1996. (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Payne Reacts to State of the Union, 23 January 1996. (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Payne Warns of Failure to Increase Debt Ceiling, 25 January 1996. (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Payne Announces Nominations to U.S. Service Academies, 26 January 1996. (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Editorial Endorsements of the Coalition Budget. (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Financial Aid Information Available From Payne's Office, 1 February 1996. (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Payne Sponsors Art Competition for High School Students, 15 February 1996. (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Payne Praises USTR Kantor for U.S.-Canada Agreement to End Unfair Lumber Imports, 16 February 1996. (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Floor Speech - Black History Month, 28 February 1996. (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - House Approves Blue Ribbon Commission on Gambling, 5 March 1996. (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Payne Backs Bill on Health Insurance Reform, 7 March 1996. (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Payne Announces E-Mail Address for Congressional Office, 12 March 1996. (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Town Meeting Card Mailing, 13 March 1996. (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - House Moderates Forge Bipartisan Welfare Compromise, 22 March 1996. (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Testimony - Payne Before House Budget Committee, 22 March 1996. (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Payne Announces April Series of One-on-One Visits, 25 March 1996. (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - UVA Health Plan Selected for Medicare Demonstration Project, 17 April 1996. (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - Payne Testifies for Moton School in Farmville, 18 April 1996. (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - FAA Grant Awarded to Charlottesville Airport, 22 April 1996. (Box 47, Folder 24)
  - Payne Sponsors Art Competition for High School Students, 8 May 1996. (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - Column - House Passes Strong Anti-Crime Measures, 10 May 1996. (Box 47, Folder 26)
  - Payne Praises USTR for Preliminary Chinese Retaliation List, 17 May 1996. (Box 47, Folder 27)
  - Payne, Warner Open Prince Edward's Sandy River Reservoir, 20 May 1996. (Box 47, Folder 28)
  - Payne Supports Small Business Jobs Act, 22 May 1996. (Box 47, Folder 29)
  - Floor Speech - Support for NIST/Manufacturing Extension Program, 29 May 1996. (Box 47, Folder 30)
  - Sandy Level Post Office Opening, 1 June 1996. (Box 47, Folder 31)
  - Payne Praises U.S. Customs for Action Against Transshippers, 3 June 1996. (Box 47, Folder 32)
  - Payne Announces EDA Water Grant for South Hill, 4 June 1996. (Box 47, Folder 33)
  - Fifth District Housing Conference Set for July 8 in Farmville, 5 June 1996. (Box 47, Folder 34)
  - Payne on Durbin Amendment to FY97 Agricultural Appropriations Act, 12 June 1996. (Box 47, Folder 35)
  - Payne, Others Introduce Pro-Textile Legislation, 13 June 1996. (Box 47, Folder 36)
  - Statement on the Textile and Apparel Global Competitiveness Act, 13 June 1996. (Box 47, Folder 37)
  - Payne Introduces Fifth District World Wide Web Site, 14 June 1996. (Box 47, Folder 38)
  - Fifth District Housing Conference on July 8, 3 July 1996. (Box 47, Folder 39)
  - Payne Hosts Final Annual Housing Conference, 9 July 1996. (Box 47, Folder 40)
  - Payne Appears with Interns, 9 July 1996. (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - House Defeats Amendment to Scrap EDA, 24 July 1996. (Box 47, Folder 42)
  - Payne Announces August Community Visits, 24 July 1996. (Box 47, Folder 43)
  - Payne Appears with Interns, 26 July 1996. (Box 47, Folder 44)
  - Payne Announces Funding for Danville Armory, 30 July 1996. (Box 47, Folder 45)
  - Payne Supports Welfare Reform Legislation, 31 July 1996. (Box 47, Folder 46)
  - Payne Asks President to Support Welfare Reform, 31 July 1996. (Box 47, Folder 47)
  - Payne Community Visits Schedule for August, 2 August 1996. (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - I-73 Road Rally, Martinsville, 15 August 1996. (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Payne, Burr Send OMB Tobacco/FDA Letter, 22 August 1996. (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Payne, Others Introduce Hurricane Relief Bill, 11 September 1996. (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Payne Asks USDA to Declare Southside Disaster Area, 11 September 1996. (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Payne Announces Run for Lt. Governor, 16 September 1996. (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - President Signs Military Construction Bill/Danville Armory, 18 September 1996. (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Home Builders Association of Danville/Pittsylvania County, 23 September 1996. (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Vocational Industrial Clubs of America Students, 25 September 1996. (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - House Passes Water Resources Development Bill, 26 September 1996. (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Richmond Crusade for Voters Letters, 28 September 1996. (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Column - Congress Passes More Anti-Crime Measures, 11 October 1996. (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Dominion 2000 Conference Letter, 11 October 1996. (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Study of Moton School to Begin, 20 November 1996. (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Goode Named to Agriculture Committee, 22 November 1996. (Box 48, Folder 15)
- Series V. General Office Files, 1988-1996., Extent: 1 box. (Box 49)
  There is one box of office files containing information on Payne's chief of staff Mark T. Bowles, including his financial disclosure statement, as well as a small amount of constituent correspondence, a staff handbook, an analysis of a staff seminar, visitors' register, and other items.
  Alphabetical.
  - Analysis of Weekend Seminar, 29 September - 1 October 1979. (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Bank Checks Issue, 1991. (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Bowles, Mark T. (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Bowles, Mark T. - CLE Credit. (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Bowles, Mark T. - Financial Disclosure Statement, 1996. (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1995. (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Employee Handbook, 1996. (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Oath of Office, 1995. (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Visitor Register, 1988-1995. (Box 49, Folder 9)
- Series VI. Campaign Files, 1992-1997., Extent: 33 boxes. (Box 50-82)
  The campaign files contain information relating to Payne's campaigns for Congress in 1992 and 1994, but the vast majority of the files concern his unsuccessful run for lieutenant governor of Virginia. Payne announced his resignation from Congress on 5 February 1996, and his bid for lieutenant governor on 16 September 1996. He lost the race to John Hager in the November 1997 election. The campaign files contain letters sent to Payne upon his retirement from Congress, opposition research, media files, candidate questionnaires, debate preparation information, press releases issued by Don Beyer, who was the Democratic nominee for Governor, event schedules, campaign literature, election results, issues and opinion research and polling information prepared by consultants, campaign plans and strategies, policy ideas and information, and message development. There is a substantial amount of information concerning fundraising, including budgets, campaign contribution and expenditure reports for Payne and other candidates submitted to the State Board of Elections, contacts, donor lists, plans and projections, phone call lists, fundraising event files, and copies of donation checks and lists of deposits. There is also a large campaign banner at the end of the collection. There is additional campaign material in the Special Media series.
  - AARP/VOTE. (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Accomplishments - 100th and 101st Congress. (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Affinity Groups. (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Affirmative Action. (Box 50, Folder 4-5)
  - African-American Radio. (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Agelasto, Peter - Virginia Beach. (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Aging. (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Agriculture - Contacts. (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Alliance for Lower Electric Rates Today (ALERT). (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Alumni Giving - VMI. (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - American Tobacco Suits. (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Andrews, Coleman - "Talk Back" WINA Interview. (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Announcement, 16 September 1996. (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Announcement Tour. (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Appomattox Golf Tournament, 29 May 1997. (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Bancard Systems, Inc.. (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Barger, Phil - Waynesboro and Staunton. (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Baughman Company. (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Beyer. (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Beyer - Governor. (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Beyer's List. (Box 51, Folder 6-8)
  - Beyer Press Releases. (Box 51, Folder 9-12)
  - Bills/Expenses. (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Bonitt, Jay. (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Bowles, Mark T. - Receipts. (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Brochure. (Box 52, Folder 4-5)
  - Budget. (Box 52, Folder 6-8)
  - Business and Professional Women's Clubs (BPW). (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Call Sheets. (Box 52, Folder 10-12)
  - Call Sheets. (Box 53, Folder 1-5)
  - Call Sheets - Cold Calls. (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Call Sheets - Home Numbers. (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Call Sheets - Need Action. (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Call Sheets - Need Info. (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Call Sheets - Need to be Researched. (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Call Sheets - September. (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Call Sheets - September 1-13. (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Call Sheets - To Do, Misc.. (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Calls. (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Calls on the Road. (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Campaign, 1992. (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Campaign, 1994. (Box 54, Folder 8-10)
  - Campaign, 1994 - Clippings. (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Campaign, 1994 - Literature. (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Campaign Budget. (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Campaign Finance Disclosure Act Summary. (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Campaign Literature. (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Campaign Plan. (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Campaign Workers' Receipts. (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Gov. Tom Carper - Reception for LFP, Wilmington, Delaware, 30 September 1997. (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Carter, Mary Rae. (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Central Committee Meeting, 6 December 1997. (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Charlottesville Fundraising. (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Charlottesville Lists. (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Charlottesville Phone Call Lists. (Box 55, Folder 11)